KENNETH JOHNSON

352-519-6016

KennethRJohnson5150@yahoo.com

Hard-working electrical professional offering a history of dedication to workplace safety and adherence to OSHA standards.

Reliable and quality-centered with demonstrated success in exceeding client expectations.

Dependable with 4 years of apprentice experience.

Well-versed in installations, repairs and system maintenance.

Strong attention to detail and problem-solving skills.

Resourceful bringing excellent communication and teamwork

illustrated over 13 years of industry experience.

Ambitious and eager to learn with superior work ethic.

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2022- DECEMBER 2023 (FULL-TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK QUALITY LABOR MANAGEMENT- CECIL FIELD AIRPORT -

- Running pipe
- Fire alarm
- Lighting controls

OCTOBER 2020 –APRIL 2022 (FULL--TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK

1200&5TH APARTMENTS -CCS/OWENS ELECTRIC

Running pipe

SEPTEMBER 2017 – SEPTEMBER 2020 (FULL--TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK

FORT MACON -CCS/ISLANDS MECHANICAL

- Running Pipe
- Lighting controls

JULY 2015- AUG 2017 (FULL--TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK UF HEALTH CANCER HOSPITAL -, CONSTRUCT CORP

- Running Pipe
- Pannel Termination
- Wire Termination

OCTOBER 2012 – MAY 2014(FULL--TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK APPRENTICE ELECTRICIAN -PRESTON LINK ELECTRIC

- Worked in a team-based environment to accomplish projects.
- Put in new electrical components, fixtures and motors.
- Operated hand and power tools and diagnostic equipment to complete various
- aspects of jobs.
- Gathered required tools and equipment for each task to increase efficiency.
- Followed all relevant electrical and building codes for each job.
- Keep work areas clean, neat and free of hazards.
- Maintained organization, cleanliness and safety in work areas.
- Measured and prepared supplies for electrical tasks.
- Listened to directives of senior electrical professionals to complete efficient tasks.
- Reviewed blueprints and electrical schematics to perform tasks to specifications.
- Adhered to company standards and OSHA regulations for work site safety.
- Dug trenches and created holes to pull conduit and install supports.
- Performed installation, maintenance and tests of electrical energy systems and
- components by safely using all equipment and tools.
- Completed semi-skilled and skilled work under supervision of fully qualified
- supervisors.
- Assisted with electrical installation tasks, added new wiring and adjusted breaker
- hoxes
- Examined and tested electrical systems to locate loose connections or other faults
- and make proactive repairs.
- Collaborated with more knowledgeable professionals to grow understanding of
- principles and construction standards.
- Inspected existing wiring to identify short circuits.
- Keep work areas clean, neat and organized for efficient operations.
- Verified measurements and made accurate cuts to avoid wasting materials on job
- sites.
- Utilized knowledge and equipment to test wiring and other system parts for electrical
- flow and function.
- Resolved issues with existing systems and replaced malfunctioning parts.
- Utilized measuring and testing instruments such as ammeters, ohmmeters,
- voltmeters and testing lamps accurately, efficiently and safely to complete
- installations and repairs.
- Demonstrated strong foundation of safety knowledge and implemented industry best
- practices.
- Built controllers and panels to complete system installations.
- Set up equipment and configured settings for optimal performance.
- Transported required supplies and employees from headquarters to job site using
- company vehicles.
- Managed repairs and maintenance work on client systems and confirmed system
- adherence to coding requirements.

NOVEMBER 2010 – JULY 2012 (FULL--TIME) 40 HOURS WORKED PER WEEK

APPRENTICE ELECTRICIAN - BURGESS & DUDLEY

- Worked in a team-based environment to accomplish projects.
- Put in new electrical components, fixtures and motors.
- Operated hand and power tools and diagnostic equipment to complete various
- aspects of jobs.
- Gathered required tools and equipment for each task to increase efficiency.
- Followed all relevant electrical and building codes for each job.

EDUCATION

SANTA FE COLLEGE GAINESVILLE, FL UNITED STATES

SKILLS

- Power Tool Knowledge
- Electrical System Modification
- Electrical Codes Familiarity
- Electrical Engineering Certified
- Calibration Tools
- Schematics and Blueprints
- Local and State Regulations
- Wiring Installations
- Electrical Diagnostics
- Electrical Maintenance and Repair
- Hand and Power Tools
- Power Cable Connection
- Field Sketching
- Parts Fabrication
- Hazard and Defect Detection

- Circuit Continuity Assessment
- Hand and Power Tool Operation
- Lock Out-Tag Out Procedures
- Blueprint Reading
- Conduit and Pipe Laying
- Business Management
- Transformer Connection
- Supply Control
- Local Codes Compliance
- Electrical Systems Testing
- Malfunction Diagnostics
- Wire Insulation
- Root Cause Analysis
- Layout Planning

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Given Upon Request